Nyasha Green

NyashaGreenn@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/nyashathechampion/



Scan for a look into my work or go here: https://greennc.github.io/Master-Portfolio/

Professional Summary

Full Stack Developer graduate of the Midlands Technical College Tech Hire program. 4.5+ years of customer service, problem solving, organization, and leadership. Fluent in multiple programming languages and skills. Aiming to leverage my advanced technical skills and quick learning to build and create a better future.

Technical Skills

Web Programming: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, SEO, Adobe Photoshop, Gimp, Bootstrap 3 & 4, PHP, jQuery, GitHub

Software: Microsoft Office, SharePoint, WordPress, MySQL, AWS

Operating Systems: Windows, iOS, Android

Professional Experience

U.S CENSUS BUREAU, Columbia, SC

Census Field Supervisor

Jul 2019 - Present

- Compile, record, and code results or data from interview or survey, using computer or specified form.
- Identify and report problems in obtaining valid data.
- Collect and analyze data, such as studying old records, tallying the number of outpatients entering each day or week, or participating in federal, state, or local population surveys as a Census Enumerator.
- Supervise or train others and maintain staff records.
- Teach field representatives the basics of data collection and accuracy in a classroom setting.
- Ensure accurate payroll information is completed in the system.

CHANDLER CREDIT REPAIR, Columbia, SC

Owner

Aug 2017 – July 2019

- Conducted investigations to determine causes of poor credit while proactively planning a strategy toward repair.
- Established successful contacts with customer, companies, and other parties involved in the building process to set expectations, prepare documents, develop an action plan, and confirm facts.
- Worked directly with 15+ customers weekly to follow up on identity theft and adherence to established financial action plan.
- Installed security software and hardware that protected dozens of sensitive information.
- Grew assets by over \$10,000 per customer by providing financial literacy.
- Marketed to over 3,000 people weekly with email campaigns and knowledge of social media marketing.

NATIONWIDE INSURANCE, Columbia, SC

Sales Manager/Training and Development Lead

Feb 2016 - Jan 2019

- Answered customers' questions about credit terms, products, prices and availability for Auto, Property, and Life Insurance.
- Supervised the company's workforce, which involved delegating tasks to staff members and scheduling.
 Analyzed data to determine which areas of the company needed improvement, provided input and trimmed excess costs.

- Automated previously manual billing process, accelerating customer payments and improving billing accuracy by more than 15%.
- Configure security settings or access permissions for groups or individuals.
- Identify the causes of networking problems, using diagnostic testing software and equipment.
- Troubleshoot network or connectivity problems for users or user groups.

VERIZON WIRELESS, Elgin, SC

Technical Support Team Lead

Jan 2015 - Feb 2016

- Supported 12 tech support specialists and inspectors who conducted 100+ trouble shoot and support action items per week.
- Answer user inquiries regarding computer software or hardware operation to resolve problems. (iOS, Android, Windows)
- Maintain records of daily data communication transactions, problems and remedial actions taken, or installation activities.
- Read technical manuals, confer with users, or conduct computer diagnostics to investigate and resolve problems or to provide technical assistance and support.
- Refer major hardware or software problems or defective products to vendors or technicians for service.
- Develop training materials and procedures, or train users in the proper use of hardware or software.

Education

MIDLANDS TECHNICAL COLLEGE, Columbia, SC

December 2019

Full Stack Web Development Course

UNIVERSITY OF SOUTH CAROLINA, Columbia, SC

December 2014

B.A. African-American Studies